# KRIS RENALDI

South Plainfield, NJ | (732) 593-7798 | krenaldi@comcast.net

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/krenaldi | Portfolio: https://krenaldi.github.io/ | GitHub: https://github.com/krenaldi

#### SUMMARY

Dedicated Full Stack Developer/Software Engineer with extensive customer service, technical training and management, and project management experience along with expertise in troubleshooting and network administration and desire to learn new things. Familiar with the following:

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, API, JSON, SQL, SASS

Tools: Git/GitHub, Gulp, NPM, Node.js, MySQL, NoSQL, Heroku, Firebase

Libraries/Frameworks: Bootstrap, Express, REACT, jQuery, MongoDB, Backbone, Knockout

Software: Visual Studio, MS Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Outlook & Visio, Adobe Photoshop & Acrobat

Operating Systems: Windows, MacOS, UNIX, Linux, Cisco

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Front-End Web Developer, Udacity
Six-Sigma Green Belt
Certified Cisco Network Administrator (CCNA)
2015
2009
2004

#### **PROJECTS**

**Common Ground** | React, NoSQL, JavaScript, APIs | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/Common-Grounds-Redux Live https://krenaldi.github.io/Common-Grounds

 Incorporated User Authentication for users to login by email and password or social media login and stores login information along with profile information and contact list into a MongoDB NoSQL Database.

**MeVite** | MySQL, Node.js, Express, Sequelize | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/MeVite Live https://mevite.herokuapp.com/

- Incorporated Passport.js for user registration and authentication by saving user information in a Sequelize database.
- Configured the database to also save event information and contacts for tracking attendance.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rutgers University Coding Bootcamp, Somerset, NJ Full Stack Developer, May 2019 – November 2019

Studied and participated in exercises on the latest of web technologies such as Node, Express, MongoDB, and React.

- Led a team of four students to develop projects and assisted them with problem-solving/troubleshooting issues on their projects.
- Responsible for the management and versioning of the code for all projects using Git and Github. Resolved any conflicts that
  occurred from merging code from different students and coached them on best practices on how prevent such conflicts.
- Implemented user authentication to work with MySQL and Mongo databases on all projects.

## AT&T, Piscataway, NJ

VPN Technical Manager, October 2015 – May 2019

Subject matter expert on ordering software and service. Led online training for domestic new hires who were managing the installation and activation of VPN with BVOIP service.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance by having my orders activated and billed before target of 90 days and was consistently a top 5 performer on the team.
- Reduced backlog of 600+ open orders by 80% by having my team follow up with clients as to whether they want service or to cancel.

### MIS/BVOIP Technical Manager, April 2010 - October 2015

Provided in-person training and coaching at overseas office. Developed and updated training documentation and assisted with troubleshooting for MIS and BVOIP ordering.

- Managed and coached a team of anywhere between 6 to 21 people depending on the product I was supporting.
- Slashed end-to-end cycle time for service ordering by several days and reduced number of rejects and defects to almost zero with the overseas team.

# Process Engineer, September 2008 - April 2010

Trained and coached new hire agents for MIS & BVOIP service ordering. Developed new hire training documentation and assisted with the onboarding process for new MIS and BVOIP engineers.

• Earned Six Sigma Green Belt and worked with Quality Management team on a Service Delivery Six Sigma Project to streamline the process for a BVOIP product which saved the company an estimated \$823K annually.

# MIS Provisioning Technical Engineer, May 2000 - September 2008

Assisted clients with their network design and architecture in order for their networks to communicate over the AT&T backbone from their datacenter and performed performance management review and troubleshooting to ensure communication was up and stable.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance with an average of 98% (exceeding the target of 90-95%) and Cycle Time with an average of 28 days (shorter than the target of 30 days). As a result of my performance, my team exceeded the On-Time Performance target with a 96% average and Cycle Time of 29 days.
- Earned 7 Commitment to Excellence awards awarded by customers and sales account teams for providing outstanding customer service.
- Project leader for several high-profile clients such as La-Z-Boy, Pepsi, Office Depot, and Motel 6.

### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Development, Rutgers University, Somerset, NJ, Oct 2019
Bachelor of Arts, Digital Media & Political Science, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ